<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux">
  <section title="Actions" id="actions">
    <subsection title="BlowFlyer">
      <picture file="images/blowflyer.png" alt="Blow Flyer">
        The BlowFlyer or BaloonTux action should be a temporary
        limited action in which Tux fills his body with air (helium?!)
        and is thus able to fly for a short time, ie as long as he can
        go without breathing. The end of the flight should be
        announced by Tux changing color and catching for air.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="ButtJump">
      <picture file="images/buttjump.png" alt="Butt Jump">
        The ButtJump is a smash attack onto the ground, which
        generates a small shockwave which affects all enemies in a
        near radius. Reaction to the shockwave for enemies might be to
        fall upside down or something similar. The ButtJump might also
        be used to break special tiles in the ground. The ButtJump is
        triggered by pressing and holding the down-key while in a
        jump. The ButtJump can't be interruppted.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Ice Flower">
      <picture file="images/iceflower.png" alt="Ice Flower">
        The IceFlower could be one of the extra that Tux can collect
        it might be able to resize him to SuperTux or give him other
        special abbilities.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Slider">
      <picture file="images/slider.jpg" alt="Slider">
        Tux will be able to make use of smooth terrain my using the
        slide action. By using the slider action Tux will jump on its
        belly and thus slide speedy down the hill. Terrain that is
        formed like a ramp should allow him to make huge jumps, which
        would be impossible without the slide action. While sliding
        downhill Tux shall be invulnerable by normal enemies, howewer
        special enemies with spikes or so, might still be able to stop
        him. <br /> Exact details on how the sliding will work have to
        be worked out, but it might get a rather central role in
        gameplay.
      </picture>
      <img src="images/slider2.png" alt="Slider" />
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Flapping">
      <picture file="images/flapping.png" alt="Flapping">
        Once in air Tux should be allowed to flap with his wings. They
        are not enough to let him fly, but should allow him to get
        some additional air-time (like a small double-jump).
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Soap" alt="Soap">
      <p>
        Tux migth be able to eat some soap and thus be able to spit
        out bobbles, bubbles them self should be useable as steps to
        reach higher places and might be able to caputer enemies.
      </p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Rope" alt="Rope">
      <p>
        Tux will be able to use a rope (in one form or another). The
        rope should be usefull for both swinging around and for
        capturing or disableing enemies.
      </p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Running">
      <picture file="images/sprite.png" alt="Running">
        SuperTux might be able to run, running will enable higher and
        wider jumps and other things that require some kind of
        'boost'. If running will be automatically or require the press
        of a 'run' button, hasn't been decided and might depend on how
        the rope is used
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Unsorted">
      <screenshot file="images/actions" />
      <screenshot file="images/actions2" />
    </subsection>
  </section>
</page>
