<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux">
  <section title="Development">
    This page  should act as a collecting place for ideas,
    graphics and other stuff surrounding the SuperTux development.
    None of it should be taken as final, but more as an source of
    inspiration and brainstorming.
  </section>

  <section title="Actions">
    <subsection title="BlowFlyer">
      <picture file="images/blowflyer.png">
        The BlowFlyer or BaloonTux action should be a temporary
        limited action in which Tux fills his body with air (helium?!)
        and is thus able to fly for a short time, ie as long as he can
        go without breathing. The end of the flight should be
        announced by Tux changing color and catching for air.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="ButtJump">
      <picture file="images/buttjump.png">
        The ButtJump is a smash attack onto the ground, which
        generates a small shockwave which affects all enemies in a
        near radius. Reaction to the shockwave for enemies might be to
        fall upside down or something similar. The ButtJump might also
        be used to break special tiles in the ground. The ButtJump is
        triggered by pressing and holding the down-key while in a
        jump. The ButtJump can't be interruppted.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Ice Flower">
      <picture file="images/iceflower.png">
        The IceFlower could be one of the extra that Tux can collect
        it might be able to resize him to SuperTux or give him other
        special abbilities.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Slider">
      <picture file="images/slider.jpg">
        Tux will be able to make use of smooth terrain my using the
        slide action. By using the slider action Tux will jump on its
        belly and thus slide speedy down the hill. Terrain that is
        formed like a ramp should allow him to make huge jumps, which
        would be impossible without the slide action. While sliding
        downhill Tux shall be invulnerable by normal enemies, howewer
        special enemies with spikes or so, might still be able to stop
        him. <br />
      </picture>
      <img src="images/slider2.png" />
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Unsorted">
      <screenshot file="images/actions" />
      <screenshot file="images/actions2" />
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section title="Enemies">
    <subsection title="Evil Penguin">
      <picture file="images/evil_penguin.png">
        The Evil Penguin should look similar to Tux, it will probally
        have another color and another shaped bill. Ranges of attack
        might be something simple such as spitting balls or eggs at
        Tux. There might even be multiple levels of evil penguins with
        different behaviours (fire, ice).
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Mr. Bomb">
      <picture file="images/mrbomb.png">
        Pretty much every game has some kind of exploding enemy, so
        SuperTux should have something like that too. For the moment
        this should be our Mr. Bomb, a plain and simple Bomb running
        on its tiny feed.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Mr. IceBlock">
      <picture file="images/mriceblock.png">
        Mr. IceBlock could be the most basic enemy in SuperTux, he
        just walks around without having any 'special attacks' or
        something like that. Jumping on Mr. IceBlock should flatten
        him and thus kill him.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Unsorted">
      <screenshot file="images/enemies" />
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section title="Tiles">
    <img src="images/tiletype.png" />

    <p>
      SuperTux should feature 5 basic tile shapes:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>empty</li>
      <li>full</li>
      <li>100% slope</li>
      <li>50% slope</li>
      <li>200% slope</li>
    </ul>
    
    <p>
      In addition to them it will feature them in mirrored form and in
      a form that allows two 50% tiles to form a smooth slope. With
      these basic tile shapes it should be possible to form reasonably
      smooth circles and smooth shapes into the terrain.
    </p>
  </section>

  <section title="Dieing">
    <p>
      In MarioBros1 one went from being SuperMario/FireMario to being
      a small Mario to being a dead on the next enemy touch. Lives
      where limited, there where no continues. MarioAllStars later
      added the ability to restart from a given World.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      In MarioBros3 one lost only one ability at a time, so
      FireMario/RacoonMario <arrow/> SuperMario <arrow/> SmallMario
      <arrow/> dead. SuperMarioWorld went the same as MarioBros3 but
      provided an additional extra-slot, that could host one extra and
      release it on request, thus restoring the abilities. Continues
      where provided per World, reset points in the world itself where
      provided by doors, that stayed open even after a continue. Reset
      points in the levels where not provided, since the levels where
      relativly short this wasn't a problem.
    </p>

    <p>
      Yoshis Island used a completly different concept, instead of
      having special abilites, Yoshis stays pretty much the same all
      the time (some items can allow Yoshi to spit fire and such, but
      these are eaten and lost after a short time, there are no
      permanent extras). On enemy contact BabyMario is released from
      Yoshi and floats around, he can be catched again, so Yoshi has
      pretty much unlimited energie if one manages to catch BabyMario
      in time.  Time counts down from max. 30 <arrow/> to 0, up to 10
      energie points are automatically refreshed, the rest needs the
      collection of items. Progress was saved per level, going forward
      and backward to older levels is possible.
    </p>

    <p>
      Mario64 and MarioSunshine used the concept of energie. In
      Mario64 energie is easily recovered by simply jumping into
      water. In MarioSunshine energie is recovered by collecting
      coins(?). No reset points in normal levels, since levels where
      split in small puzzles that needs to be solved. The jump'n run
      levels had a reset point at half of the level.
    </p>

    <p>
      Falling into a hole in the ground leads to death in all Marios.
    </p>

    <p>
      The trend is after all to make dieing less fatal, loss of energy
      is easily recovered in most games, but requires a bit of
      work. Reset points are provided in addition. So the frustration
      is keep rather low. Progress is often saved per level now
      instead of per world, thus not forcing you to replay levels
      again and again. Lives are of not much use since Yoshis Island,
      they only limited the amount of times one can use a reset point
      in the level itself, world wise they have no effect.
    </p>

    <p>
      So how should dieing in SuperTux work? Keeping frustration low
      and the reset point frequent should be a goal, however it should
      not be made too easy (ie not providing a quick-save in the level
      itself). Saving on the worldmap should happen on a per level
      basis, not per world. Saving should be automatic, replaying
      levels should be possible. Reset points in the level should be
      provided, given that the levels are long enough. Enemy contact
      should cause the current extra to be lost.
    </p>

  </section>
</page>