<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux">
  <section title="News">
    <news>
      <item date="21. August 2005">
        The <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download page</a> now has additional
        binary packages for SuperTux 0.1.3, including a version for MacOS X 10.3 or later as well as an (unofficial) Windows build.
      </item>
      <item date="09. July 2005">
        SuperTux 0.1.3 has been released! New features include a second Bonus Island with 28
        new levels as well as custom world map support and a few bugfixes.
        Get the source package at the <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>,
        binary packages will follow soon.
        A compatible version of Flexlay with world map support is available from the
        Flexlay SVN repository; you can download it by using the following command:
        "svn checkout svn://svn.berlios.de/flexlay/branches/flexlay-0.0.2"
        A big "Thank you" goes out to everyone who contributed to this release!
      </item>
      <item date="30. June 2005">
        The level submission deadline for SuperTux 0.1.3 is over - the second Bonus Island
        will contain 20 new levels, four from the SuperTux Team and sixteen contributed by
        players. Expect a release around next week.
        For all of you waiting for milestone 2: We still have no idea when it'll be ready,
        but we are all putting a lot of our free time into it. There has already been quite
        some progress, and there's more to come.
      </item>
      <item date="13. June 2005">
        To (hopefully) keep you happy while waiting for milestone 2, we decided to release
        another Bonus Island featuring a bunch of new contributed and official levels. The
        webmaster of the <a href="http://cd.bromley.ac.uk/supertux/">SuperTux Fan Site</a>
        provided an assorted set of levels that have been submitted to his site to be
        included on Bonus Island 2. If you created a level that you would like to appear in
        the next release, <a href="mailto:supertux-devel@berlios.de">please send it to us</a>
        during the next two weeks.
      </item>
      <item date="3. April 2005">
        After a rather long break where everyone has been busy with other
	things, we are finally back on SuperTux. The main goals of milestone 2
	were discussed in an IRC meeting yesterday; the
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Meeting_log_(2005-04-02)">meeting log</a>
        is available on the
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/">SuperTux wiki</a>.
      </item>
      <item date="2. December 2004">
        It looks like we have our first fansite. You can find it at
        <a href="http://cd.bromley.ac.uk/supertux/">SuperTux: The Fan Site</a>.
        It includes game information, tips, cheats and more.
      </item>
      <item date="25. October 2004">
        Better late than never. We now have a Mandrake RPM, Mac OS X binary and
        a BeOS package in our <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>.
      </item>
      <item date="26. August 2004">
        A SuperTux 0.1.2 RPM for RedHat, Fedora and ASP Linux is now available,
        as well as a Windows binary. You can get them from the
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>. More packages are on
        there way.
      </item>
      <item date="24. August 2004">
        SuperTux 0.1.2 has been released! It features 22 new levels from both 
        the SuperTux team and contributors. You can wait for the various
        packages to be released or you can
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">get the source tarball now</a>. The new levels
        in SuperTux 0.1.2 can be found under the <strong>Bonus Levels</strong>
        menu.
      </item>
      <item date="14. July 2004">
        A new SuperTux 0.1.1 Mac OS X binary is available that fixes a start-up crash in OS X 10.2.
        We also now have a SuperTux 0.1.1 Fedora Core 2 RPM available.
        As always, you can get them from our
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>.
      </item>
      <item date="29. June 2004">
        SuperTux 0.1.1 now has SuSE RPMs available. You can get them from our
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>.
      </item>
      <item date="19. May 2004">
        Supertux 0.1.1 now has binaries for Windows and Mac OS X 10.3.x as well
        as an <a href="http://www.autopackage.org">autopackage</a> installer
        in our <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>.
      </item>
      
      <item date="11. May 2004">
        SuperTux 0.1.1 is out, still the same game as 0.1.0, features
        however a much improved font, some minor bugfixes and finally
        a build in editor. A Win32 build is available as well, you can
        get it in the <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="3. May 2004">
        Windows Binary for SuperTux is released, go to the
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a> to download it.
      </item>

      <item date="2. May 2004">
        SuperTux Milestone1, aka 0.1.0 has been released, featuring 26
        levels, a worldmap and completly reworked graphics, go to the
        <a href="http://supertux.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Download/Installation">download section</a> to download it.
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>
</page>
