<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<tux:newsfeed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:tux="http://supertux.github.io/">
  <!-- arguably this should be split into one file per news entry -->
  <tux:news date="May 21 2015">
    <p>
      We (The SuperTux Development Team) have put our heads together,
      and we are going to try to officially release Milestone 2 sometime
      in December. We currently are planning on that month, so right now
      is a crucial time to have people bug testing. If you would like to
      help with bug testing you can find the latest downloads in the
      <a href="download.xml">Download</a> section. As always, if you
      come across a bug ( or what might be one, feel free to report it
      in our <a href="https://github.com/SuperTux/supertux/issues">Bug Tracker.</a>
      If you would like to help us get this release out you can find more
      information on our <a href="contact.xml">contact section.</a>
    </p>
  </tux:news>
  <tux:news date="May 20 2015">
    <p>
      Whewph, what alot of changes, but here you go. We spent the last
      few days re-doing the website and updating its info.
    </p>
    <p>
    The latest release (0.3.5a) Brought the following improvements over earlier versions:
    </p>
    <ul style="font-size:85%;color:grey">
      <li>move to SDL2 for graphics rendering</li>
      <li>glow effects</li>
      <li>new badguys: iceflame, ghostflame, livefire, goldbomb, smartblock</li>
      <li>new bonuses: coinrain, coinexplode</li>
      <li>statistics improved</li>
      <li>icy island levels tweaked</li>
      <li>new sounds</li>
      <li>massive improvements to localization</li>
      <li>efficiency tweaks</li>
      <li>menus reworked</li>
      <li>addon manager improved</li>
      <li>new tilemap: halloween</li>
      <li>new powerups: air- and earth-flower</li>
      <li>support for horizontal gradients in levels (add
        (direction "vertical|horizontal") to your level)</li>
      <li>A 64 bit Windows installer</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Here is a link to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLhVp_BLj959LBm30GjVOQMyGQFOG-yKzm">video footage</a> of SuperTux 0.3.5a courtesy of o11c.
    </p>
  </tux:news>
  <tux:news date="May 2015">
    <p>
      Yay! 3 weeks after our 0.3.5 release we bring you release 0.3.5a,
      which fixes a ton of bugs and we added a <em>64 bit Windows installer</em>!!
      As always, if you run into bugs, or would like to join us in
      developing this game, you can find us on <a href="https://github.com/SuperTux/supertux">Github</a>.
    </p>
  </tux:news>
  <tux:news date="April 2015">
    <p>
      <em>We are excited to bring to you 0.3.5 beta 1 git snapshot!</em>
      We put a ton of changes and improvements into this release.
      Head over to the <a href="download.xml">Downloads Section</a> to try it out!!
    </p>
  </tux:news>
  <tux:news date="2003">
    <p>
      The <em>Milestone 1</em> release of SuperTux features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>9 enemies</li>
      <li>26 playable levels</li>
      <li>Software and OpenGL rendering modes</li>
      <li>configurable joystick and keyboard input</li>
      <li>new music</li>
      <li>completely redone graphics</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Together with a little story, we hope to provide a good
      gaming experience with this first Milestone release.
    </p>
    <p>
      SuperTux is available for Windows, Linux, MacOSX as well as
      numerous other more exotic systems.
    </p>
  </tux:news>
</tux:newsfeed>
