<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux - Milestone 2 - Version 0.2.0">
  <section title="Milestone 2 Goals">
    <p>
      Now that Milestone1 is out and up and running, its time to take
      some preperations for Milestone2. Goals should of course
      include:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>new enemies</li>
      <li>at least one new tileset</li>
      <li>15-30 new levels</li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      However that are of course just generic goals that pretty much
      apply to any Milestone, more detail goals follow below and will
      be extented and refined over the comming month:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>intelligent horizontal and vertical scrolling as seen in
        most later jump'n runs, which means tha camera should
        automatically change the viewpoint so that the player has a
        good view onto things that are comming onto him, it should
        also be possible for the player to manually turn the camera to
        move to the left/right, the camera should also be sensitive to
        the speed of the player, so if he runs fast the camera should
        give more to see infront of the player, then when walking
        at normal speed, Yoshi Island demonstrates this camera behaviour quite well
      </li>

      <li>
        together with vertical scrolling levels of course should have
        both variable heights and width
      </li>

      <li>
        parallax scrolling backgrounds should be build out of tiles
        instead of plain huge jpg/png graphics, multilpe configurable
        background layers would be good as well (ie. gradient,
        parallax tilemap 1, parallax tilemap 2, playfield bg,
        interactive playfield, playfield fg, parallax tilemap
        foreground)
      </li>

      <li>
        the game should support sublevels, so that one can walk
        through pipes or doors to enter other sections of a level
      </li>

      <li>
        butt-jump as described on the development page should be
        implemented, in addition to that there would be a need for a
        new tiletype that reacts on a butt-jump and gets smashed
      </li>

      <li>
        flaping as described on the described should be implemented,
        it should basically provide the player with an additional 'up
        boost' in the down-phase of a jump and giving him more ability
        to land precisly.
      </li>

      <li>
        one-tile problem should be fixed, meaning Tux should be able
        to fall through small 1 tile wide holes, instead of just
        walking over them, this could/should be fixed by the use
        collision/tile shapes that are not rects, but rects with round
        edges or elipses
      </li>

      <li>
        Tux should be able to jump again/bounce while jumping on an
        enemy (ie. by holding down the jump button), this is standard
        Mario behaviour
      </li>

      <li>
        non-square tiles, as the ones used for sliding would be good
        to have, sliding itself isn't strictly necessary for
        Milestone2, could be suspended for Milestone3
      </li>

      <li>
        At least one final boss is a minimum for this release, a
        second mini-boss would be good as well.
      </li>

      <li>
        info-boxes that present a dialog-window on jump would be good
        to teach the player new moves and actions
      </li>

      <li>
        multilanguage support (via gettext or such) might be good with
        the number of text increasing
      </li>

      <li>
        ice and fireflower should get more specifc meaning and
        abilities
      </li>
    </ul>
  </section>
</page>