<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux">

  <section title="Current State">
    <p>
      The Computer/Geek theme (laptop enemies, bsods) which is visible
      in the current CVS version will be dropped and be replaced with
      something more comical.
    </p>
  </section>

  <section title="Enemies" id="enemies">
    <subsection title="Evil Penguin">
      <picture file="images/evil_penguin.png">
        The Evil Penguin should look similar to Tux, it will probally
        have another color and another shaped bill. Ranges of attack
        might be something simple such as spitting balls or eggs at
        Tux. There might even be multiple levels of evil penguins with
        different behaviours (fire, ice).
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Mr. Bomb">
      <picture file="images/mrbomb.png">
        Pretty much every game has some kind of exploding enemy, so
        SuperTux should have something like that too. For the moment
        this should be our Mr. Bomb, a plain and simple Bomb running
        on its tiny feed.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Mr. IceBlock">
      <picture file="images/mriceblock.png">
        Mr. IceBlock could be the most basic enemy in SuperTux, he
        just walks around without having any 'special attacks' or
        something like that. Jumping on Mr. IceBlock should flatten
        him and thus kill him.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Mr. Crystal">
      <picture file="images/mrcrystal.png">
        When Tux jumps on MrCrystal, MrCrystal will break into pieces.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Spiky">
      <picture file="images/spiky.png">
        Spiky has spikes which makes it impossible for Tux to kill him
        by jumping on him.
      </picture>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Unsorted">
      <screenshot file="images/enemies" />
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Sprites">
      <p>
        The following is a list of basic sprites that are needed, more
        can never be bad, but it should especially made sure that the
        few here are good and smooth. The width/height are only meant
        as guideline, a bit larger/smaller is ok and recomment, since
        overlap of graphics can produce a more cleaner look in the
        final game. Some of the other pages here contain sketches of
        the sprites.
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>SmallTux - 32x32, ie. Tux without extras</li>
        <li>Tux - 64x32, ie. Tux with 'size' extra</li> 
        <li>SuperTux - 64x32, ie Tux with 'size' and 'firepower' extra</li>

        <li>Mr. Iceblock - 32x32 most basic enemy, needs two or three
          frames for a walking, at least one for dieing</li>
        
        <li>Mr. Bomb - 32x32 a basic enemy that explodes after being
          kill, needs two or three for walking, at least two for being
          dead plus at least one for explosion</li>

      </ul>
    </subsection>

  </section>
</page>
