<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux - Milestone 1 - Version 0.1.0">
  <section title="Milestone 1 Goals">
    <p>
      The goal of <strong>Milestone 1</strong> (also known as 0.1.0),
      is to produce a useable and fully playable game with the current
      MarioBros1-style SuperTux engine. The timeframe for the
      development should be one or two month. The goal is not to
      create a groundbreaking jump'n run with Milestone1, but simply
      to produce something of reasonably quality with the current
      engine. Later Milestones might improve on the work done in
      Milestone1, but for the moment we should focus on stuff that is
      doable in one month and not speculate all that much about the
      future.
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>extent the engine with whatever features are requested by
        the level designers (moving platforms, more enemy types)</li>

      <li>create around 15 levels of variing difficulty and arange
        them to a completly playable game with a nice raising
        difficulty</li>

      <li>extent the tilesets to look better, add more varity</li>

      <li>create animated sprites for Tux, SuperTux, FireTux</li>

      <li>create sprites for enemies (MrBomb, MrIceBlock, etc.)</li>

      <li>add music and sound effects to the game</li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Since there is are already people working on the tileset,
      leveleditor and engine, there is especially a need for level
      designers and gameplay testers and of course artists for the
      music and sound. If somebody is good at drawing animated sprites
      he is also very welcome. Since the goal for Milestone1 should be
      just to create a playable game with the current engine without
      extenting it all that much, it should be possible to reach the
      goal within one month.
    </p>
  </section>

  <section title="Tasks">
    <ul>
      <li>
        fix up the current engine back into a usable state, ie.
        MarioBros1 like, no back-scrolling or other funky stuff that
        could get too complicated
      </li>

      <li>
        create new graphics or update the current ones where doable
      </li>

      <li>
        create a handfull of levels and connect them to a playable
        game
      </li>
      
      <li>
        create a little credits-screen/extro or something like
        that
      </li>

      <li>
        The final game should contain around 16 levels, 10 should be
        the minimum number of levels to be developed before the
        release. More levels are welcome, but shouldn't be a
        requirement for the release. Qualitity should be more
        important then pure quanitity.
      </li>
    </ul>

    <subsection title="Contact">
      <p>
        Development is mainly coordinated via IRC and the SuperTux
        Mailing list.

        coordinated over the IRC channel #supertux at irc.freenode.net
        and there is also a mailing list available at.
      </p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section title="Graphics">

    <subsection title="Font">
      <p>
        The font has to be of a fixed-with for all letters, ie. the
        size of the letters can be anything, but has to be constant
        for all letters of a given font. The current font is (based on
        the old one, just 'gaussion blur (iir) 2', 'threshold 112', 'border
        2'):
      </p>
      
      <img src="images/font.png" alt="" />

      <p>
        Unless somebody provides a better font, it will simply get a
        few more colors and get included in the game like it is (M/N
        and a few more letters might be a bit buggy).
      </p>
    </subsection>

  </section>
</page>
