<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="SuperTux - Milestone 1 - Version 0.1.0">
  <section title="Milestone 1 Goals">
    <p>
      The goal of <strong>Milestone 1</strong> (also known as 0.1.0),
      is to produce a useable and fully playable game with the current
      MarioBros1-style SuperTux engine. The timeframe for the
      development should be one or two month. The goal is not to
      create a groundbreaking jump'n run with Milestone1, but simply
      to produce something of reasonably quality with the current
      engine. Later Milestones might improve on the work done in
      Milestone1, but for the moment we should focus on stuff that is
      doable in one month and not speculate all that much about the
      future.
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        fix up the current engine back into a usable state, ie.
        MarioBros1 like, no back-scrolling or other funky stuff that
        could get too complicated, keep especially care of a sane jump
        behaviour, which can easily go wrong
      </li>

      <li>extent the engine with whatever features are requested by
        the level designers (moving platforms, more enemy types)</li>

      <li>create around 15 levels of variing difficulty and arange
        them to a completly playable game with a nice raising
        difficulty. More levels are welcome, but shouldn't be a
        requirement for the release. Qualitity should be more
        important then pure quanitity, so levels that don't hold up
        with the rest should be stripped out.
      </li>

      <li>extent the tilesets to look better, add more varity</li>

      <li>create animated sprites for Tux, SuperTux, FireTux</li>

      <li>create sprites for enemies (MrBomb, MrIceBlock, etc.)</li>

      <li>add music and sound effects to the game</li>

      <li>create a webpage for the game itself (ie. not this
        development webpage)</li>

      <li>
        create a little credits-screen/extro or something like
        that
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Since there is are already people working on the tileset,
      leveleditor and engine, there is especially a need for level
      designers and gameplay testers and of course artists for the
      music and sound. If somebody is good at drawing animated sprites
      he is also very welcome. Since the goal for Milestone1 should be
      just to create a playable game with the current engine without
      extenting it all that much, it should be possible to reach the
      goal within one month.
    </p>
    <p>
      There hasn't been a final decision on the look of SuperTux, but
      unless somebody comes up with something better, the image below
      shows the look that the game will have. The final game will of
      course differ in details, this is just a mookup in Gimp.
    </p>
    <screenshot file="images/supertux-gamescreen" />
  </section>

</page>

